<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="indian-news.xslt"?>
<news xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="news.xsd">
    <article>
        <title>India reports highest single-day spike of COVID-19 cases in 2022</title>
        <date>2023-02-24</date>
        <author>PTI (Press Trust of India)</author>
        <content>India on Thursday reported its highest single-day spike of COVID-19 cases in 2022 with 1,06,933 fresh infections, pushing the country's cumulative tally to 42,108,142, according to the Union Health Ministry data updated at 8 am. The death toll has climbed to 4,89,477 with 725 more fatalities, the data showed. The active cases have increased to 6,91,382, comprising 1.64 per cent of the total infections, while the recovery rate was recorded at 97.64 per cent, the ministry said. The case fatality rate was recorded at 1.16 per cent. Maharashtra reported the highest number of fresh cases at 21,359, followed by Kerala (19,158) and Tamil Nadu (11,157).</content>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title>RBI keeps key interest rate unchanged at 4%, projects GDP growth at 8.5% in FY24</title>
        <date>2023-02-23</date>
        <author>Business Today</author>
        <content>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) on Wednesday kept the repo rate, its key interest rate, unchanged at 4 per cent, amid concerns over rising inflation. The central bank also projected India's gross domestic product (GDP) growth at 8.5 per cent in the financial year 2023-24, up from its earlier estimate of 7.9 per cent.</content>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title> India records highest-ever exports of $42 billion in February</title>
        <date>2023-02-24</date>
        <author>Economic Times</author>
        <content>India's merchandise exports in February reached an all-time high of $42 billion, up 35.6 per cent from the same month last year, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce and Industry. The increase in exports was driven by growth in sectors such as engineering goods, gems and jewellery, and pharmaceuticals.</content>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title>India successfully test-fires new missile capable of hitting targets up to 1,000 km away</title>
        <date>2023-02-23</date>
        <author>NDTV</author>
        <content>India on Monday successfully test-fired a new missile, the Agni-P, which is capable of hitting targets up to 1,000 km away. The missile, developed by the Defence Research and Development Organisation, is a derivative of the Agni series of missiles and is designed to be used by the Army.</content>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title>Delhi government announces free electricity up to 200 units for domestic consumers</title>
        <date>2023-02-21</date>
        <author>India Today</author>
        <content>The Delhi government on Sunday announced free electricity up to 200 units for domestic consumers, in a move aimed at providing relief to households struggling with high electricity bills. The scheme is expected to benefit over 33 lakh domestic consumers in the national capital.</content>
    </article>


    <article>
        <title>India's Central Bank Cuts Interest Rates to Boost Economy</title>
        <date>2023-02-24</date>
        <author>Rajiv Sharma</author>
        <content>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has cut its key interest rate by 25 basis points to
            5.25% in an effort to stimulate economic growth. The move comes amid concerns about
            slowing growth and rising inflation in the country. The RBI also announced several other
            measures to support the economy, including a relaxation of banking regulations and an
            increase in liquidity.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Navy Conducts Successful Test of Nuclear-Capable Missile</title>
        <date>2023-02-23</date>
        <author>Prakash Kumar</author>
        <content>The Indian Navy has successfully test-fired a nuclear-capable ballistic missile
            from a submerged submarine in the Arabian Sea. The missile, which has a range of over
            1,500 kilometers, hit its target with high precision. The test is part of India's
            efforts to bolster its strategic deterrence capabilities.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Government Launches New Program to Promote Electric Vehicles</title>
        <date>2023-02-22</date>
        <author>Shruti Gupta</author>
        <content>The Indian government has launched a new program aimed at promoting the adoption of
            electric vehicles in the country. The program includes financial incentives for buyers
            of electric vehicles, as well as the establishment of new charging infrastructure across
            the country. The government hopes that the program will help to reduce India's
            dependence on imported oil and curb air pollution.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Army Foils Infiltration Attempt by Terrorists from Pakistan</title>
        <date>2023-02-21</date>
        <author>Deepak Singh</author>
        <content>The Indian army has foiled an infiltration attempt by a group of terrorists from
            Pakistan in the border state of Jammu and Kashmir. The terrorists were attempting to
            cross the Line of Control (LoC) when they were spotted by Indian troops, who engaged
            them in a gunfight. Three terrorists were killed in the operation, while the rest fled
            back across the LoC.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Government Announces New Measures to Tackle Air Pollution</title>
        <date>2023-02-20</date>
        <author>Manoj Sharma</author>
        <content>The Indian government has announced several new measures to tackle air pollution in
            the country, including a ban on the sale of diesel generators and the introduction of
            stricter emissions standards for vehicles. The measures are part of a broader effort to
            improve air quality in India, which has some of the most polluted cities in the world.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Tennis Player Sania Mirza Wins Doubles Title at Dubai Open</title>
        <date>2023-02-19</date>
        <author>Nisha Patel</author>
        <content>Indian tennis player Sania Mirza has won the women's doubles title at the Dubai
            Open, partnering with her Ukrainian teammate Elina Svitolina. The duo defeated the
            French-Slovenian pairing of Kristina Mladenovic and Kaja Juvan in straight sets to claim
            the title. This is Mirza's first doubles titlesince returning to the tour after taking a
            break to have a baby.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Parliament Passes Bill to Ban Cryptocurrencies</title>
        <date>2023-02-18</date>
        <author>Arun Kumar</author>
        <content>The Indian parliament has passed a bill that would ban all private cryptocurrencies
            in the country, including Bitcoin and Ethereum. The bill also provides for the creation
            of a central bank digital currency (CBDC) by the Reserve Bank of India. The move is
            aimed at curbing the use of cryptocurrencies for illegal activities and maintaining
            financial stability in the country.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Space Agency Successfully Launches Communication Satellite</title>
        <date>2023-02-17</date>
        <author>Rajesh Verma</author>
        <content>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) has successfully launched a
            communication satellite into orbit. The satellite, named GSAT-18A, will provide
            telecommunications and broadcasting services to remote areas of the country. The launch
            was carried out using ISRO's Geosynchronous Satellite Launch Vehicle (GSLV), which has a
            success rate of over 90%.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian Farmers Protest Against New Agriculture Laws</title>
        <date>2023-02-16</date>
        <author>Priya Singh</author>
        <content>Thousands of farmers in India are protesting against new agriculture laws that they
            say will hurt their livelihoods. The laws, which were passed by the government last
            year, seek to liberalize the agriculture sector by allowing farmers to sell their
            produce to anyone, anywhere in the country. However, many farmers fear that the laws
            will lead to the dismantling of government-run markets and leave them at the mercy of
            big corporations.</content>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Indian State of Uttar Pradesh Announces New Investment Promotion Policy</title>
        <date>2023-02-15</date>
        <author>Vikram Singh</author>
        <content>The Indian state of Uttar Pradesh has announced a new investment promotion policy
            aimed at attracting more businesses to the state. The policy offers a range of
            incentives to companies that invest in the state, including tax breaks, land at
            discounted rates, and assistance with obtaining permits and approvals. Uttar Pradesh is
            one of the fastest-growing states in India and has a large and diverse economy.</content>
    </article>
</news>